Website Privacy Policy

Lexia Learning Systems LLC, a [Cambium Learning® Group company](https://www.cambiumlearning.com/) (“Lexia”) is the developer of the Lexia® technology-based learning solutions. We take the privacy of our customers seriously. We are committed to safeguarding your privacy while providing a personalized and valuable service.

1\. Overview

This Privacy Policy explains the data processing practices of Lexia, and how Lexia collects and uses your personal information when you visit or access [www.Lexialearning.com](https://www.lexialearning.com/) or our other commercial websites (“Websites”), or when you interact with us in other on-line and off-line sales or marketing activities. This privacy policy also describes how Lexia shares and secures your personal information, as well as your choices regarding the use, access and correction of your personal information. For our privacy policies concerning the collection and use of personal information of school or district students or staffs that is collected within and through use of our online subscription products and related services, including [www.mylexia.com](http://www.mylexia.com/) and the MyLexia mobile application, please refer to our [Application Data Privacy Policy](https://legal.lexialearning.com/legal/application-privacy.html). If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any questions about these practices please contact our Privacy Officer by e-mail at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com).

Information provided by you may be requested from one of our Websites or those of our affiliates under the Lexia, the Cambium Learning Group or one of the Cambium Learning Group brands, or from one of our reputable co-marketing partner sites that represent our brands on their own websites under their company and/or brand name. In the event that you provide us with personal information for the purposes of free registration and you later make a purchase, whether directly from us or facilitated by one of our e-commerce partners, we will collect and use your personal information according to our stated policies that are posted and available for your review at the time of purchase.

As described in this Privacy Policy, we use your personal information to provide and improve our services. By visiting our Website or using our services, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We encourage you to periodically review this privacy policy as it may change at any time at our sole discretion. Our Website may contain links to third party sites, which are not subject to this privacy policy. Lexia does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices or content on these sites. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit.

2\. Information Collected

Personal information is collected by Lexia. We collect personal information about you (your “Personal Information”) through:

* The use of inquiry and registration forms
* The purchase process when you buy any of our products or services
* The provision of your details to us either online or offline

The elements of your Personal Information that we collect under this policy may include:

* Name
* Job title
* Company name
* Personal or professional contact and demographic information, shipping and billing addresses, phone and fax number
* Mobile telephone number
* E-mail address
* IP address, device information, activity information and browser information
* Payment details such as credit card information and transaction history
* Market research data such as customer usage patterns

3\. Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

We use Personal Information under this privacy policy for various business purposes which may include:

* Providing our customers with a personalized service and support.
* Engaging in transactions and communications with our customers.
* Processing orders, registrations and inquiries.
* Conducting market research and surveys.
* Running competitions.
* Measuring interest in and improving our website, products, and services.
* Providing our customers with information about products and services we offer. You may stop the delivery of marketing emails by following the instructions accompanying a particular communication or by contacting us at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com).
* Protecting rights or fulfilling obligations required by law, regulation or contract.
* Resolving disputes, collecting fees, protecting against fraud, and troubleshooting problems

We use the information you provide when placing an order to complete that order and to service your account. We do not share this information with outside parties except: 1. to the extent necessary to complete that order or to provide you with services by way of our service providers or contracted partners (e.g., payment processing, sales partners servicing your account, third-party shipping, cloud computing infrastructure and hosting providers, business analytics, customer support); or 2. to successors in title to our business; or 3. in accordance with legal and regulatory requirements or to respond to a government subpoena or other government request; or 4. as necessary, in Lexia’s sole discretion, to protect the perceived rights, safety and property of Lexia, users of our Websites or services, and the public; or 5. with the parent organization, affiliate or subsidiary entities of Lexia to manage the personal information as joint controllers.  We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

You may sign-up to receive email or newsletter or other marketing communications from us.  If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails we send to you or at your member profile on our website or by contacting us at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com).

Other than as set out above, you will be notified when personal information about you will be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to have us share such information.

We also use information in aggregate form (so that no individual user is identified):

* To build up marketing profiles
* To aid strategic development
* To audit usage of the Website

4\. Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Devices

We use cookies or similar tracking devices to help personalize your use of our Websites.  A cookie is a small piece of information which is sent to your computer’s hard drive by the web server so that the website can remember who you are. This information may include information relating to your use of our Websites, information about your computer such as the computer’s IP address and browser type, demographic data, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data and, if you arrived at our Website via a link from a third party site, the URL of the linking page.  We do not use tracking devices to track your usage of the Internet on other sites not operated by Lexia.

We use cookies and other tracking devices to analyze trends, administer the Website, understand and analyze our users’ movements around the Website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

We also use information from cookies for purposes, which may include:

* Identifying returning users and registrants
* Enabling users to move more easily around our Websites
* Tracking how our users use of our Websites to better develop our sites in accordance with user requirements
* Building up a demographic profile of our Website users

If you do not want to help us learn how to improve our Websites, products, offers and marketing strategy, you may indicate your preference on the cookies preference center on the Website, and/or you may choose to set your Web browser to not accept certain cookies. Similar preference settings options may be available on your mobile device. You can control the use of certain cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our Website or service. Further information on how to prevent cookies from being stored on your computer can be found on [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) under the ‘manage cookies’ section. Alternatively, go to the help menu within your Internet browser.

From time to time we may permit third party companies to set cookies on Lexia Websites for purposes which may include market research, revenue tracking or to improve functionality of the site.

From time to time we may permit third party companies to set cookies on Lexia Websites for purposes which may include market research, revenue tracking or to improve functionality of the site.

We may place or recognize technology on your browser or device when you visit our Sites for purposes of serving you targeted advertising (also referred to as "online behavioral advertising").  We also work with third party advertising companies who place their own cookies or similar technology on your browser or device when you visit our Sites and other websites to serve customized advertisements to you as you browse the Internet. As noted above, you can set your device or browser to accept or reject most cookies, or at least notify you in most situations that the technology is offered. As an additional step, these advertising companies may participate in one of the following self-regulatory programs for online behavioral advertising, with corresponding user opt-outs:

* Networking Advertising Initiative ([http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/)) (US Only)
* Digital Advertising Alliance ([http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)) (US Only)
* European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance ([http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) (EU Only)
* Digital Advertising Alliance - Canada ([http://youradchoices.ca/choices](http://youradchoices.ca/choices)) (Canada Only)
* DAA App Choices Mobile App (Mobile Devices Only) - For mobile devices (e.g., smartphone, tablets), you may consider downloading the DAA AppChoices Mobile App to manage such technology.

Please note that even if you reject such technology, you may continue to receive advertisements, but the advertisements will not be tailored to your browsing activities and interests.

5\. Security 

Lexia has implemented an Information Security Program and security measures designed to help ensure that our users’ Personal Information is protected against unauthorized access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction, or accidental loss. Although we make reasonable efforts to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that thieves could find a way to thwart our security systems. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com).

6\. Transfer of Personal Information

The Internet is a global environment. Websites, software, services and programs delivered and accessed through the Internet necessarily involve the transmission and processing of personal data, sometimes on an international basis, depending, for example, on where the user is located. When personal information is provided to Lexia through the Websites, the information will be processed from and stored on servers located in the United States and globally, and by using the Websites, you acknowledge and give Lexia authorization to such transfer, processing and storage.

Lexia has implemented appropriate cross-border transfer solutions, notably in accordance with Article 49 of the General Data Protection Regulation, to provide adequate protection for transfers of certain personal data, including notably from EEA and the UK to the U.S. To the extent permitted or required by applicable law, your use of this site constitutes your consent to the transfer of your personal data to Lexia in the United States.

7\. Access to Personal Information & Request Process

Upon request and as provided herein, Lexia will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by contacting us. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

Where required by applicable law, and notably by the **General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)** for residents of the UK and European Union, you have the right to obtain confirmation of the existence of certain Personal Data relating to you, to verify its content, origin, and accuracy, as well as the right to access, review, port, delete, or to block or withdraw consent to the processing of certain Personal Data (without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal), by contacting us as detailed below.  **In particular, you have the right to object to our use of Personal Data for any direct marketing and in certain other situations at any time**.  Please note that certain Personal Data may be retained as required or permitted by applicable law.  

We may charge the allowable fee under applicable law for provision of this information. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. Please note that additional information may be required to confirm and enable us to assist with your request.  The timeframe to address the request may vary depending on the nature of the request, however, we will endeavor to address the request as promptly as possible, typically within thirty (30) days and as may be required by law.

Notice to California Consumers

If you reside in California, we are required to provide additional information to you about how we use and disclose your information, and you may have additional rights with regard to how we use your information. We have included this California-specific information below.  

* **CA Personal Information**. Consistent with Section 2 of this **_Lexia Website Properties Privacy Policy_**, we collect certain categories and specific pieces of information about individuals that are considered "Personal Information" in California ("**CA Personal Information**"), specifically:
    * **_Personal and Other Identifiers or Characteristics_**: _such as first name and last name, personal or professional contacting information, mailing address, telephone number, e-mail address, unique personal identifier, IP, device, and online activity information, age, date of birth, gender, demographics, username and password to our Websites or services;_
    * **_Commercial Information_**_: such as payment details, credit card information and purchase or transaction history._ 
    * **_Sources_**_._ We may collect certain categories of CA Personal Information from you and other third parties as described in Sections 2 and 4 of this _**Lexia Website Properties Privacy Policy**._ 
* ​**Use of CA Personal Information**_._ Consistent with Section 3 of this _**Lexia Website Properties Privacy Policy**,_ we may use CA Personal Information for business or commercial purposes. Please see Section 3 for more details_._
* **CA Personal Information Sold or Disclosed For Business Purposes**_._ 
    * In the preceding twelve months, we may have shared CA Personal Information for business purposes, or we may have “sold” (as defined under CCPA) some categories of CA Personal Information.
* **California Consumer Rights**. Subject to certain exceptions, as a California resident, you may have the following rights to your CA Personal Information: (i) Access. Request access to your CA Personal Information that we collect, use, disclose, or sell; (ii) _Deletion_. Request deletion of your CA Personal Information; and (iii) _CA Personal Information Sold or Disclosed For Business Purposes_. Request information about the CA Personal Information we have "sold" (as defined under CCPA) or disclosed for business purposes within the preceding 12 months. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may be required to retain some of your CA Personal Information and certain CA Personal Information is strictly necessary in order for us to fulfill the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. 
* **Exercising California consumer rights**. If you are a California resident and wish to exercise any of these rights, please: (a) submit your request using our California webform available [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/27aac3ab-c36e-4457-81d4-9773ba27887e/72f89fd2-fe4b-41ce-8c0a-406f9b88a0da.html); (b) log into your account to make any updates or submit a request; (c) contact us as described in this **_Lexia Website Properties Privacy Policy_**, or (d) call the following toll-free number 800-507-2772. When submitting your request, you may be asked to provide certain information, which may include additional proof of identification, so that we can verify your identity and validate the request. We are not responsible for requests that are not sent or submitted properly, or that do not have complete information. Please note that you are limited by law in the number of requests you may submit per year. We will not discriminate against you by offering you different pricing or products, or by providing you with a different level or quality of products, based solely upon you exercising your rights to your CA Personal Information.  
* **Do Not Sell My Personal Information**. If we “sell” (as defined by CCPA) your CA Personal Information to a third party, as a California Resident, you have the right to opt-out of the sale of your CA Personal Information. If you wish to exercise this right, please click [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/27aac3ab-c36e-4457-81d4-9773ba27887e/72f89fd2-fe4b-41ce-8c0a-406f9b88a0da.html), contact us as described in this **_Lexia Website Properties Privacy Policy_**, or call the following toll-free number 800-507-2772. To the extent that you elect to designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, they must identify that they are contacting us as agent and will be required to provide appropriate documentation including written signed authorization by you, proof of your identity, and verification of their identity; or a valid, designated power of attorney as required under the California Probate Code.  We may require additional proof of authority or may need to contact you directly to validate the request. If you are under the age of 16, we will not sell your CA Personal Information without proper consent. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, please contact us by contacting the Privacy Officer at [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com) or writing to:

Privacy Officer  
Lexia Learning Systems LLC  
300 Baker Avenue, Suite 202  
Concord Massachusetts 01742  
Email: [privacy@lexialearning.com](mailto:privacy@lexialearning.com)  
Phone: (978) 405-6200

8\. Personal Information – Retention

We may retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with our services, comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, verify performance, resolve disputes and enforce our rights and agreements.

9\. Children Under 13

We do not intentionally collect any information on children under 13 years of age from our Websites. We will undertake to delete any details of such users where a parent, guardian or authorized school official has notified us that any such details have been obtained.

10\. Changes to this Policy

This Website privacy policy is effective as of the date indicated above. We will review and may update this Website privacy policy from time to time to reflect changes to our privacy practices and in accordance with changes in legislation, best practice or Website enhancements. If we make material changes to this Website privacy policy, we will explain those changes from our prior practices when they are posted, and we will send a notice to the account owner/administrator email address that you provided to us upon enrolling for use.

_Last reviewed: June 29, 2023_

_Last updated and effective as of: July 1, 2023_
